George S. McGovern Papers Series 5: Audiovisual Materials, 1957-1984 (bulk 1968-1972 )
Princeton University Library. Special Collections.
- Series 5: Audiovisual Materials, 1957-1984; 105.42 linear feet 110 boxes Approximately 1,785 items
  - Subseries 5E: Undated Material, 1967-1968; 29 linear feet 30 boxes
    - Kennedy, Ted-McGovern for Senate, undated; 737; 2 minutes 40 seconds 16mm (Box 847)
    - Kennedy, Ted: Platte Bridge Part I, undated; 22; 2-inch 1 box (Box 848)
    - KIHO, Mitchell, South Dakota, undated; 174; 1 box (Box 848)
    - KXAB-TV, undated; 16mm portion of 1 box (Box 848)
      Includes materials with identifiers: 1725, 1727.
    - Ladies, #6, undated; 5 minutes 16mm color) (Box 848)
      Includes materials with identifiers: 205, 210-214, 507, 691, 709.
    - LA Speech, Munich, undated; 1184; 1 box (Box 848)
    - LA Speech, Munich, undated; 1185; Cut-Up 1 box (Box 848)
    - LBJ Policy, undated; 194; 50 seconds 16mm (Box 848)
    - Lenox High School, undated; 906; 1 box (Box 848)
    - Lenox High School #1-2, undated; portion of 1 box (Box 848)
      Includes materials with identifiers: 916, 907.
    - Liberal Party Dinner, New York City, October 4 no year; 1635; 1 box (Box 848)
    - Lindley for McGovern, undated; 98; 3/4 inch on 1.5-inch reel 16mm (Box 848)
    - Lindley for McGovern, undated; 192; 1.5 inches, no core 16mm (Box 848)
    - McGovern LL Tags, undated; portion of 1 box (Box 848)
      Includes materials with identifiers: 397, 645.
    - Madison, undated; 591; 1 box (Box 848)
    - Madison Fund Raiser, undated; 872; 1 box (Box 848)
    - The Making of a President 1968, undated; 384; 1 box (Box 848)
    - Mansfield 90 Seconds IDs, undated; 40; 5 minutes 2-inch (Box 848)
    - Massachusetts-Quincy and Nebraska Primary Speech, undated; 1631; 1 box (Box 848)
    - Mass Act, undated; 136; master) 1 box (Box 849)
    - Ohio Idea to 94, undated; master) 1 box (Box 849)
      Includes materials with identifiers: 132, 133, 1116.
    - Master #5, undated; 1121; 1 box (Box 849)
    - McGovern #1, June 16 no year; 1337; 1 box (Box 849)
    - McGovern, 4 spots, undated; 1420; 1 box (Box 849)
    - McGovern, #2 Interviews, undated; 1423; 1 box (Box 849)
    - McGovern 31st Anniversary Party, October 13 no year; 106; 16mm 1 box (Box 849)
    - McGovern 132, undated; 1772; 16mm 1 box (Box 849)
    - McGovern American Responsibility, undated; 177; 1 box (Box 849)
    - McGovern-Anderson, undated; 499; 16mm 1 box (Box 849)
    - McGovern at Brookings, undated; 257; 1 box (Box 849)
    - McGovern/Cloca, undated; 45; 2-inch 1 box (Box 849)
    - McGovern Debate, October 31 no year; 365; 1 box (Box 849)
    - McGovern Dinner, #1-3, undated; 984; 1 box (Box 849)
    - McGovern ECN Push, undated; 16mm 3 boxes (Box 850, Box 851, Box 852)
      Includes materials with identifiers: 467, 469-470.
    - ECN, undated; 119; 5 minutes 16mm A and B roll) (Box 853)
    - McGovern-Freeman, KOTA-TV, undated; 1726; 12 minutes 15 seconds 16mm (Box 853)
    - McGovern for President, #100, undated; 101; 60 seconds 16mm (Box 853)
    - McGovern for President, #101, undated; 102; 60 seconds 16mm (Box 853)
    - McGovern for President, #102, undated; 100; 30 seconds 16mm (Box 853)
    - McGovern for Senate 1,2,3,4, undated; 712; 4 minutes (Box 853)
    - McGovern for Senate 2,3,4, 6, 8, 9, undated; 702; 4 minutes 30 seconds (Box 853)
    - McGovern-Holum, undated; 14 minutes 16mm (Box 853)
      Includes materials with identifiers: 392, 514.
    - McGovern-Keogh Interview, undated; 694; 13 minutes 40 seconds (Box 853)
    - McGovern Master Delegates, June 30 no year; 546; 1 box (Box 853)
    - McGovern Mini-Convention: Shriver Nominated, August 8 no year; 1373; 1 box (Box 853)
    - McGovern Music, undated; 398; 16mm 1 box (Box 853)
    - McGovern on Vietnam, undated; 1010; 1 box (Box 853)
    - McGovern Pulls, undated; 85; 16mm R-2 TRK 1 box (Box 853)
    - McGovern Radio-1972 Primary, undated; portion of 1 box (Box 853)
      Includes materials with identifiers: 1247, 1248.
    - McGovern Referendum #1-#4, undated; 677-680; 1 box (Box 853)
    - McGovern Report-Jeff Smith, undated; 1149; 1 box (Box 853)
    - McGovern-PR #3, undated; 923; 1 box (Box 853)
    - McGovern Six Mistakes, undated; 118; 5 minutes 16mm H Track (Box 854)
    - McGovern Six Mistakes, undated; 84; 16mm 1 box (Box 854)
    - McGovern and South Dakota-A Proven Partnership, undated; 643; 5 minutes 16mm (Box 854)
    - McGovern Speech, undated; 1278; 1 box (Box 854)
    - McGovern-Staff Educational Material, undated; 16mm portion of 1 box (Box 854)
      Includes materials with identifiers: 495, 503.
    - McGovern-Staff #2, May 17 no year; 16mm portion of 1 box (Box 854)
      Includes materials with identifiers: 522, 525, 1729.
    - McGovern and Staff, undated; 496; 16mm 1 box (Box 854)
    - McGovern Takes Reagan; Mass. v. The Pentagon, undated; 30 seconds (Box 854)
      Includes materials with identifiers: 551, 552.
    - McGovern Tape-11 Cuts, undated; 60 seconds (Box 854)
      Includes materials with identifiers: 711, 722.
    - McGovern TV Economics, October 20 no year; 1376; 1 box (Box 854)
    - McGovern U.S. Senator Demo, undated; 241; 1 box (Box 854)
    - Medicare #1, Savings Wiped Out, undated; 1687; 45 seconds 16mm (Box 854)
    - Medicare #2, The Pauper's Oath, undated; 1688; 45 seconds 16mm (Box 854)
    - Medicare #3, Man in the Middle, undated; 45 seconds 16mm (Box 854)
      Includes materials with identifiers: 1689, 1767.
    - Medicare International, undated; 191; 16mm 1 box (Box 854)
    - Meet the Candidates Spot, undated; 1107; 3 minutes (Box 854)
    - Meet the New Senator, CBS, undated; 436; 16mm 1 box (Box 854)
    - Meet the New Senators, undated; 46; 2-inch 1 box (Box 855)
    - Meet the Press Debate, undated; 1352; 1 box (Box 856)
    - Mental Health Hospital, Lenin Vocational School, undated; 1450; 1 box (Box 856)
    - MHO Speech, undated; 1453; 1 box (Box 856)
    - Middle Missouri and Ed Crafts, undated; 14 minutes 16mm (Box 856)
      Includes materials with identifiers: 493, 513.
    - Military, undated; 1683; 58 seconds 16mm (Box 856)
    - Ministry of Education, Lenin Vocational School, undated; 1456; 1 box (Box 856)
    - Mister Democrat, Pete Quinto, undated; portion of 1 box (Box 856)
      Includes materials with identifiers: 1696, 1699-1704.
    - Mondale/McGovern, undated; 668; 4 minutes 35 seconds U-Matic KCS-20 (Box 856)
    - Montana, undated; 1561; 1 box (Box 856)
    - Montana: Billings, October 16 no year; 1371; 1 box (Box 856)
    - Montoga, undated; 1254; 53 seconds (Box 856)
    - Mrs. King Endorsement, undated; 1198; 1 box (Box 856)
    - My Government is McGovernment, undated; 1285; 1 box (Box 856)
    - National Security Conference, September 21 no year; 1372; 1 box (Box 856)
    - NBC TV 555 and CBS TV 557, undated; 1070; 1 box (Box 856)
    - New Hampshire Debate with Ted Koppel, Part I, undated; 1612; 1 box (Box 856)
    - New Hampshire Primary, undated; 1554; 1 box (Box 856)
    - New Hampshire TV Debate, March 5 no year; 1383; 1 box (Box 856)
    - New Jersey with Ed Muskie, Post-Convention Labor Meeting, undated; 857; 1 box (Box 856)
    - New Mexico Part 2, undated; 148; Master 1 box (Box 856)
    - New York Hearing, undated; 1331; 1 box (Box 856)
    - New York City, Hospital P.C., June 12 no year; 149; 1 box (Box 856)
    - New York and Pennsylvania Post-Convention Speeches, undated; 874; 1 box (Box 856)
    - New York, Downtown Rochester Rally Post-Convention, undated; 873; 1 box (Box 856)
    - News Film, 6 p.m., undated; 1693; 16mm 1 box (Box 856)
    - Nixon's Broken Promises, undated; 253; 1 box (Box 856)
    - Nixon-49, America-1, undated; 1205; 1 box (Box 856)
    - Noon Luncheon Remarks, undated; 1627; 1 box (Box 856)
    - OA Cooper, undated; 172; 1 box (Box 856)
    - Ohio Primary, undated; 885; 1 box (Box 856)
    - Old Speech by Non-Entities, undated; 259; 1 box (Box 856)
    - Oregon Master, undated; portion of 1 box (Box 856)
      Includes materials with identifiers: 1432, 1439.
    - Oregon Part 2, undated; master) portion of 1 box (Box 856)
      Includes materials with identifiers: 141, 143.
    - Pachoda, Department of Justice, undated; 29; 2-inch 1 box (Box 856)
    - Paper Ballot, undated; 60 seconds 16mm (Box 856)
      Includes materials with identifiers: 732, 743.
    - Peace Machines: Dialog on a Summer Morning, undated; 1697; 1 box (Box 856)
    - Penna Master, undated; 135; 1 box (Box 857)
    - Pennsylvania-New York-Connecticut, September 13-14 no year; 1387; 1 box (Box 857)
    - Poem, McGovern Campaign, undated; portion of 1 box (Box 857)
      Includes materials with identifiers: 1380, 1381.
    - President Ford, October 9 no year; 227; 1 box (Box 857)
    - Press Club, undated; 1458; 1 box (Box 857)
    - Pretoria Press Club, Canada, undated; 1457; 1 box (Box 857)
    - Primary Day Show, County Leaders, undated; 142; 1 box (Box 857)
    - Prisoner-of-War, Wife Press Conference, Milwaukee, undated; 1202; 1 box (Box 857)
    - Property Tax Relief, Dorchester, Massachusetts, February 9 no year; 164; 1 box (Box 857)
    - Question and Answer, Education, undated; 1680; 16mm 1 box (Box 857)
    - Radio Spots: General, undated; reels A, B, C portion of 1 box (Box 857)
      Includes materials with identifiers: 215-216, 221-224, 230-235, 242-247, 564, 603, 899-901, 904, 917, 935-936, 1769-1770.
    - Radio Spots, Guggenheim Productions, 1-9, undated; portion of 1 box (Box 857)
      Includes materials with identifiers: 687-689, 696-697, 699, 701, 705-707, 713, 714, 943.
    - Radio Spots, McGovern Radio, 1-9, undated; 1244; 1 box (Box 857)
    - Radio Spots, undated; 1232; master) 1 box (Box 857)
    - Radio Spots, Black Hills, undated; portion of 1 box (Box 857)
      Includes materials with identifiers: 225-226, 592, 902.
    - Radio Spots, 7 60-Second Spots, Citizens for McGovern Committee, undated; 7 minutes Reel S (Box 857)
      Includes materials with identifiers: 236-240, 898, 950.
    - Radio Spots, Musical Ads #1-18, undated; 18 minutes (Box 858)
      Includes materials with identifiers: 370, 577, 1154.
    - Radio Spots-Brookings: The Senator Got Involved, undated; 587; 60 seconds (Box 858)
    - Radio Spots-Mitchell, undated; 566; 1 box (Box 858)
    - Radio Spots-Rapid City, undated; 565; 1 box (Box 858)
    - Radio Spots-Vermillion, undated; 605; 1 box (Box 858)
    - Radio Spots-Waterton, undated; 590; 1 box (Box 858)
    - Radio Wave I, undated; 924; 1 box (Box 858)
    - Radio Wave II, Pulls-Radio, undated; 945; 1 box (Box 858)
    - Radio Wave II, Recording Session, undated; 944; 1 box (Box 858)
    - Ramsey Clock, undated; 1415; 1 box (Box 858)
    - Recreation, undated; 20 seconds 16mm (Box 858)
      Includes materials with identifiers: 482, 485, 716, 719.
    - Reel #331, undated; 1220; 1 box (Box 858)
    - Reel #332, undated; 1230; 1 box (Box 858)
    - Reel #335, undated; 1231; 1 box (Box 858)
    - Religion, undated; 1766; 16mm 1 box (Box 858)
    - Remarkable Ingrates, undated; 179; 47 seconds (Box 858)
    - RR Effect, undated; 400; 16mm 1 box (Box 858)
    - Rushmore Start, undated; 927; roll 2 1 box (Box 858)
    - Rushmore End, undated; 925; roll 3 1 box (Box 858)
    - St. Timothy's Methodist Church, undated; 1073; 1 box (Box 858)
    - San Francisco Labor, October, undated; 1632; 1 box (Box 858)
    - Schumeler Challenge, Ag Day Statement, undated; 1617; 2 minutes 2 seconds (Box 858)
    - Schwartz Wallace Original, undated; 472; 16mm 1 box (Box 858)
    - Secretary of the Treasury, undated; 178; 1 box (Box 858)
    - Seminar at the Hilton, undated; 1292; 1 box (Box 858)
    - Senator Kennedy Spots #1-6, undated; 1242-1243; 1 box (Box 858)
    - Senator Kennedy, undated; 518; 5 minutes 16mm (Box 858)
    - Senator Kennedy, undated; 534; 60 seconds 16mm (Box 858)
    - Senator George McGoven 13 Spots, undated; 34; 50mm 1 box (Box 876)
    - Seniors, undated; portion of 1 box (Box 858)
      Includes materials with identifiers: 685, 912, 913.
    - Seniors, undated; 16mm portion of 1 box (Box 858)
      Includes materials with identifiers: 115, 642.
    - Seniors, undated; 16mm portion of 1 box (Box 858)
      Includes materials with identifiers: 86, 87.
    - Shapp TV Spots, undated; 5; 16mm 1 box (Box 858)
    - Sharecropper 75, WCCO-Radio, undated; 1630; 1 box (Box 858)
    - Signing #1, undated; 1690; 60 seconds 16mm silent) (Box 858)
    - Song, undated; 1298; 1 box (Box 858)
    - Song, Campaign, undated; 1462; 1 box (Box 859)
    - Song: Come Home America, undated; 1280; 1 box (Box 859)
    - Song: Come Home America, undated; 1286; 1 box (Box 859)
    - Song: Senator Monroney Campaign Song, undated; 1030; 1 box (Box 859)
    - Song: This is a Man, undated; 1283; 1 box (Box 859)
    - Song: Thunder in November, undated; portion of 1 box (Box 859)
      Includes materials with identifiers: 682, 946, 1279.
    - Song: We Can Change the World, undated; 1277; 1 box (Box 859)
    - Sound Effects: Room Tone, Applause, Laughter, etc, undated; 1100; 1 box (Box 859)
    - South Dakota, October 31 no year; 1422; 1 box (Box 859)
    - Southern Tour-Atlanta, Georgia Rally, undated; 1577; 1 box (Box 859)
    - Spain, Reels #324-328, undated; portion of 1 box (Box 859)
      Includes materials with identifiers: 1223, 1227, 1226, 1225, 1224.
    - Spanish Spots, undated; portion of 1 box (Box 859)
      Includes materials with identifiers: 1255, 1256, 1258.
    - Special Interests, 8 Spots, undated; 2-inch portion of 1 box (Box 859)
      Includes materials with identifiers: 67, 68.
    - Spots #1-7, undated; portion of 1 box (Box 859, Reel Reel #329)
      Includes materials with identifiers: 1157, 1221.
    - Spots #7-12, undated; 1018; 1 box (Box 859)
    - 9 Spots: Agriculture, Debate, Oven for McGovern, etc), undated; 6; 16mm 1 box (Box 859)
    - 9 spots, undated; 61; 19 minutes 30 seconds 2-inch (Box 859)
    - 9 spots, undated; 64; 5 minutes 2-inch (Box 860)
    - 13 spots, undated; 2-inch Dupe 3 boxes (Box 861, Box 862, Box 863)
      Includes materials with identifiers: 47, 48, 51.
    - Spots, undated; 455; 16mm 1 box (Box 864)
    - The McGovern Song, undated; 1 box (Box 864)
    - Spots, New, May 17 no year; 251; 1 box (Box 864)
    - Spots Wave #1, undated; 540; 5 minutes 16mm (Box 865)
    - Spots Wave #1, undated; 1144; 16mm 1 box (Box 866)
    - Spot #1 Inflation, undated; 1773; 16mm 1 box (Box 866)
    - Spot #1 Inflation, undated; 117; 16mm 1 box (Box 866)
    - Spot #1 New Era of Hope, undated; 30; 2-inch 1 box (Box 866)
    - Spot #4 Mt. Thoughts, undated; 1774; 16mm 1 box (Box 866)
    - Spot #5 Young Farmer, undated; 1775; 16mm 1 box (Box 866)
      c. 1 and c.2
    - Spot #6 Tourism, undated; 1776; 16mm 1 box (Box 866)
    - Spot #7 Eleanor, undated; 1777; 16mm 1 box (Box 866)
    - Spot #8 Children, undated; 20 seconds 16mm b/w (Box 866)
      Includes materials with identifiers: 195-196, 202, 209, 483, 490, 533, 536, 647, 1679, 1691, 1768 c.1 and c.2.
    - Spot #13, undated; 646; 16mm 1 box (Box 866)
    - Steel Mill, cont, undated; 1460; 1 box (Box 866)
    - Students, #11, undated; 5 minutes 16mm b/w (Box 866)
      Includes materials with identifiers: 203, 204, 207, 208, 690, 692, 700, 728.
    - Tape #2, undated; 726; 1 box (Box 866)
    - Tape #10, undated; 1206; 1 box (Box 866)
    - Tape #84, undated; 1316; 1 box (Box 867)
    - Texas Rally Houston, Chawcy College, undated; 272; 1 box (Box 867)
    - Thoronogs Interview for McGovern, undated; 1097; 1 box (Box 867)
    - T-Pictures R-9 McGovern HH, undated; 108; 16mm 1 box (Box 867)
    - Tracks, undated; 1146; 5 minutes 16mm A, B, H tracks (Box 867)
    - Tractor Trim, undated; 16mm A, H tracks portion of 1 box (Box 867)
      Includes materials with identifiers: 401, 649.
    - Transcripts, undated; 1598; 1 box (Box 867)
    - TV Spots, 3 Release Points of Color, undated; 1147; 16mm 1 box (Box 867)
    - U.S. Cancer Fish Investigation; Cancer Birds, undated; 622; 1 box (Box 867)
    - U.S. Senate Youth, undated; 375; 1 box (Box 867)
    - Veterans, undated; 72; 2-inch 1 box (Box 867)
    - Vietnam Speech, Pennsylvania, undated; 878; 1 box (Box 867)
    - Virginia from Rapp-Collins, undated; 545; 1 box (Box 867)
    - Wall Street Address, August 29 no year; 14 minutes 24 seconds (Box 867)
      Includes materials with identifiers: 1369, 1391.
    - War and Electronic Bombing, Illinois Primary Campaign, ADA Speech, undated; 855; 1 box (Box 867)
    - Wassell, Tom, undated; 1051; 1 box (Box 867)
    - Wisconsin: Mrs. Ella Nelson, Kenosha, undated; 1555; 1 box (Box 867)
    - Wisconsin Primary Results, undated; 153; 1 box (Box 867)
    - Wisconsin Primary, Call-in Shows, undated; 1624; 1 box (Box 867)
    - Wisconsin: Milwaukee Post-Convention Downtown Rally, undated; 858; 1 box (Box 867)
    - Wisconsin Statement, undated; 1576; 1 box (Box 867)
    - Wisconsin, Stevens Point, undated; 1452; 1 box (Box 867)
    - Wisconsin-WAKX #2, undated; 1210; 1 box (Box 867)
    - World Trade for Better Living, undated; 8; 16mm 1 box (Box 868)
    - Yale Debate Tape I-II, undated; 1621-1622; 1 box (Box 868)
    - Young Generation, undated; 60 seconds 16mm (Box 868)
      Includes materials with identifiers: 479, 480, 717.
    - Youth Wants to Know, undated; 9; 16mm 1 box (Box 868)
    - 12th World Methodist Conference, Programs 1-4, undated; 1613; 1 box (Box 868)
    - 30 Minutes With: Elizabeth Drew, undated; 765; 1 box (Box 868)
    - 68-1 to 68-2, undated; 320-321; 1 box (Box 868)
    - 69-1, undated; 319; 1 box (Box 868)
    - 70-1 to 70-4, undated; 315-318; 1 box (Box 868)
    - 71-1 to 71-6, undated; 309-314; 1 box (Box 868)
    - 71-6, undated; 322; 1 box (Box 868)
    - 71-7 to 71-10, undated; 290-293; 1 box (Box 868)
    - 71-11 to 71-19, undated; 281-289; 1 box (Box 868)
    - 71-20 to 71-22, undated; 278-280; 1 box (Box 868)
    - 71-23, undated; 308; 1 box (Box 868)
    - 71-24 to 71-31, undated; 300-307; 1 box (Box 868)
    - 71-32 to 71-36, undated; 295-299; 1 box (Box 868)
    - 71-37 to 71-45, undated; 263-271; 1 box (Box 868)
    - 92, Glenn Dure, undated; 91; 16mm 1 box (Box 868)
    - 93, undated; 92; 16mm 1 box (Box 868)
    - 362, undated; 439; 16mm 1 box (Box 868)
    - 548 McGovern, undated; 90; 16mm 1 box (Box 868)
    - 9138, undated; 73; 16mm 1 box (Box 868)
  - Subseries 5F: Unidentified Materials, undated; 28.02 linear feet 23 boxes (Box 869, Box 870, Box 871, Box 872, Box 873, Box 877, Box 878, Box 879, Box 880, Box 881, Box 882, Box 883, Box 884, Box 886, Box 887, Box 888, Box 892, Box 893, Box 894, Box 895, Box 896, Box 897, Box 898)
    Unidentified Materials includes items of all formats that lack sufficient title and/or date information to make a reliable identification. The item numbers of unidentified items have been omitted from the above inventory. In addition, the following item numbers have been withdrawn: 1164-1170 (moved to photographs); 16, 476, 1616 (empty container).
    Materials in Subseries 5F are filed by item number.